Nehemias Alcántara Santana

Email: nemiasalc56@gmail.com | Github: https://github.com/nemiasalc56

Phone: (312) 330-1206 | Chicago, IL 60622

ABOUT ME

Software Engineer dedicated to solving problems and creating efficiencies looking for a full-time position as junior fullstack web developer. Born and raised in the Dominican Republic, fluent in English and native Spanish speaker. Spent two years supporting computer literacy outreach work in my rural hometown of approximately 1,400 people. Legally authorized to work in the United States without employer sponsorship.

SKILLS

Programming JavaScript, Html5, CSS, jQuery, MongoDB, REST, Express, NodeJs, Ajax, and Python Languages Native Spanish; Fluent in English

Other Proficient in MS Suite; INFOTEP-certified Residential Electricity Installer

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Chicago, IL

Dec 2019 – Present

Software Engineering Immersive Program (12-week; 500 hours)

Project 1: https://nemiasalc56.github.io/basketball-game/ created using JavaScript, CSS, Html, & jQuery

Boost Mobile, Chicago, IL

June 2019 – Dec 2019

Sales Representative

- Identified customer needs and developed product and plan recommendations.
- Customer outreach to inform customers of ongoing promotions and new products available.
- Maintained comprehensive inventory and financial records during store operations.

Alórica, Santo Domingo, D.R.

July 2018 – April 2019

Customer Service Representative, Technical Support

• Provided Samsung Home Appliance customers with guidance to troubleshoot issues with products.

Teleperformance Hispaniola, Santo Domingo, D.R.

June 2017 - July 2018

Bilingual Customer Service Representative

• Supported Cricket Wireless customers to manage their wireless plans.

Community Technology Center (CTC), Bánica, Elías Piña, D.R.

Oct 2014 – April 2016

- Manager
 - Designed and implemented programs to improve access to technology and develop ICT skills in the community through which 50 youth and 10 adults gained computer literacy skills.
 - Trained a team of six community volunteers to lead workshops and impart computer literacy classes.
 - Maintained the functioning of the facility's equipment and operations.

Junta Central Electoral, Bánica, Elías Piña, D.R.

May 2016

Volunteer Technical Assistant, 2016 Elections

• Provided technical assistance to the polling location in Sabana Cruz, Bánica

EDUCATION

Autonomous University of Santo Domingo (La UASD), Santo Domingo, D.R.

2017-2018

Bachelor of Science, Information Technology (Licenciatura en Informática)

Federico Henríquez y Carvajal University, Baní, Peravia, D.R.

2015-2016

Bachelor of Arts. Mathematics